PAUL ADAMS

Technology Leader

9 406 Stafford Close, Franklin, TN 37069-4360

SUMMARY

Results-oriented, goal-driven technologist with 18+ years of leadership experience in software development and IT infrastructure. Diverse background includes startups to international corporations, consulting, various technology stacks, building and motivating teams, SaaS products, and strategic planning. Strong collaboration, analytical, and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Development Manager

06/2022 - Present

Ceridian

 Directs a group of 10 Android, iOS, QA, and SDIT engineers to add new features and infrastructure to the Dayforce Wallet finance app, providing users on-demand access to their earned wages.

Mobile Development Manager

09/2019 - 06/2022

Quore

(2 years, 9 months)

- Led a team of Android and iOS Developers who provided hotel industry software solutions for 85.9K monthly active users
- Applied best practices that assured a 99.9% crash-free architecture and adherence to multiple data privacy regulations
- Promoted personal skill improvement to elevate innovation, boost team productivity, and ensure high product quality

Senior Mobile Developer

06/2015 - 09/2019

Contractor

(4 years, 3 months)

- \cdot Collaborated with stakeholders and cross-functional teams to devise achievable technology roadmaps for 17 n-tier product initiatives
- Applied agile software development practices throughout the life-cycle of each project, assuring consistently on-time deliverables
- · Engineered 214 titles among 14 App Store categories
- · Designed, developed, and maintained three nonprofit websites

Information Technology Manager

U.S. Army

(16 years, 2 months)

- Coordinated and supervised the employment, operation, management, and maintenance of information technology systems worldwide in mobile and fixed facilities
- Wrote programs to handle the collection, manipulation, and distribution of data for an array of applications and requirements
- Operated telecommunications systems, including automated networks and a full spectrum of data links and circuits

PROJECTS

Mobile App Portfolio

https://adams.io/portfolio.pdf

SKILLS

Agile Leadership · Project Budgets · Analytics · Technical Writing · Swift · Objective-C · Kotlin · Java · Ruby · JavaScript · REST · GraphQL · PostgreSQL · SQLite · AWS · Azure · Firebase · CI/CD · TDD · UI/UX · Biometrics · Machine Learning · Bluetooth LE · Offshore Resourcing · Data Privacy · eAccessibility

COURSES

iOS Development Course
Devmountain, Immersive Cohort 4

IT Specialist Advanced Leader Course

U.S. Army, Honor Graduate

Ranger School U.S. Army

EDUCATION

Graduate Study, Counseling Thomas University

Bachelor's Degree, Psychology Thomas University